Gopalakrishnan Subramani

Interactive Product Spec, Sizing & Selection Apps

gopalakrishnan.subramani@gmail.com

Summary

Solution oriented technologist worked on frameworks and products that reduce complexities for developers and business users to get started, maintain and grow the application features. I architect, design and implement desktop and web applications. I solve unstructured data into structured and streamlined data. Expertise: Product Specification, Sizing & Selection Mobile Apps Manufacturing Products Search, Recommendation Algorithms Data Science, Units of Measurement User Interaction Cloud, Mobile and PC App Development Specialties: **Industrial Automation** Manufacturing Software Development Technologies: Cloud, Big-Data Mobile

Experience

Founder at Streamflex Technologies Pvt Ltd

November 2013 - Present (1 year 3 months)

Developing a smart data platform for managing, sharing product specifications for manufacturers and consumers. Publish your products specs on cloud, take it anywhere in your mobile devices, access over Data API on SaaS service cloud. Demo is available on request. Mail to stream@istream.io

Software Architect at Utthunga Technologies

November 2007 - Present (7 years 3 months)

Implemented an OPC UA based protocol independent Enterprise Application Framework which powers the user interface and device description with back-end transparently mapped to the HART, Modbus, Offline and Simulation System. Designed powerful XML based configuration system with C#, XML & Lua. Designed and implemented a FDT-DTM Device framework which supports FieldBus, ProfiBus and Hart protocol from scratch in Win32/VC++/XML Designed and implemented Hart, Modbus RTU and ASCII protocol stacks in VC++/Win32 & C#.NET Implemented self executable Firmware Installer for upgrading and downgrading millions of transmitters in C++/Win32 Led and Mentor 16+ team members on OPC DA, OPC UA, FDT-DTM and .NET/Java & Web technologies

2 recommendations available upon request

Consultant at iStreamLiner (Proprietorship)

March 2007 - January 2009 (1 year 11 months)

Worked on implementing a Remote Control Interface, a home grown, telnet based GUI test automation framework, embedded within the MFC based application Implemented a text protocol for client and server to interchange the messages and call function and read properties Implemented GUI test automated test

cases in Perl Implemented Python application to capture the user action and generate the Perl automated script when the developer does the manual testing using the RCI interface.

1 recommendation available upon request

Technical Leader at Leverage Consulting Private Ltd

June 2006 - October 2007 (1 year 5 months)

Worked on OPC DA technologies Worked on Firmware Installer application to upgrade and downgrade firmware of field device Worked on porting OPC DA based application to OPC UA based stack

Design Engineer at GE Medical Systems Pvt Ltd

July 2005 - June 2006 (1 year)

Designed and implemented a DICOM Push Library to send the images and videos to the DICOM SCP system in C++ Published detailed white papers on DICOM push. Worked on CORBA layer to remove complication found in the system Published a detailed white paper and architecture for integration between two mainstream X-ray and Vascular systems to auto start scanning in the same time Being part talent recruitment team for choosing candidate for system engineer and specialists Active participant in code review and design pattern discussions

1 recommendation available upon request

Software Engineer at Mphasis

January 2004 - June 2005 (1 year 6 months)

Internalization of Machine Vision software developed in VC++ to run on Windows 95 to Windows 2003. Worked on bug fixing, maintenance, enhancement and localization for machine vision application implemented in VC++. Fixed resource leaks which delayed the release for months. Team Lead and client contact for development and testing of the application

Student Project Guide at Freelancer

July 2002 - May 2003 (11 months)

Implemented Swing based Mail client using SMTP and POP3 in Java Implemented SNMP v2 Monitoring application for in Java, Java Swing Customized VNC protocol to send files and clipboard text in VC++ Implemented Remote Desktop sharing tool over LAN using VC++

Skills & Expertise

Python
JavaScript
Agile Methodologies
Linux
MySQL
Software Design
Product Development
Product Design

Software Architecture Mobile Applications Node.js Software Development Cloud Computing Databases .NET

Education

Gandhigram Rural Institute

Master of Science, Information Technology, 2000 - 2002

1 recommendation available upon request

University of Madras

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science, 1997 - 2000

Activities and Societies: Led C/C++ competition on inter-college meet

Interests

Startup, Mobile, Data, Scaling, Infrastructure, Business

Gopalakrishnan Subramani

Interactive Product Spec, Sizing & Selection Apps

gopalakrishnan.subramani@gmail.com



5 people have recommended Gopalakrishnan

"Gopal has built a dynamic and flexible data storage model for our mobile platform that works well on unpredictable connectivity. He helped us to design and built our mobile application from scratch. He is very agile and smart person to work with. We had a lots of fun hacking and solving problems. I highly recommend him for solving complex problems in manageable way in resource & time constrained world"

— Prashanth Rao, was Gopalakrishnan's client

"Gopalakrishnan is one of most creative, talented guy I have ever worked with. His way of tackling the problems will make him the best person to rely on for any issues. He is quick thinker and believes in smart work than hard work. Technical very strong and real asset to an organization. Above all, he is the wonderful human being. I highly recommend Gopalakrishnan and wish him good luck in future endeavours"

— **Smitha Rao, PMP**, *Project Manager, Utthunga Technologies*, worked directly with Gopalakrishnan at Utthunga Technologies

"Gopal was a great help in writing Perl test code for Banner Engineering vision sensors as well as test hooks in C++ to automate usage of the vision sensor GUI. He is very cooperative, friendly and handles situations well which do not have much definition."

— **Shawn Johnson**, *Test Engineer, Banner Engineering*, was with another company when working with Gopalakrishnan at iStreamLiner

"Gopal has been very eager to learn new things and practice those till he gets good level of confidence. I remember managing him on few design documents. He left no aspect unturned and documented the design beyond my expectations. He did not hesitate to ask when he needed some answers. He is quite ambitious in nature and keeps moving forward with persistence and hard work. All the best Gopal!"

— Anupam Arohi, Systems Specialist, GE, managed Gopalakrishnan indirectly at GE Healthcare

"Proudly saying, He is good friend of mine. Gopal is one of the most creative and calm guy. He has been very eager to learn new things and explore new things and practice those till He gets good level of confidence. He did not hesitate to ask when He needed some answers. He is quite ambitious in nature and keeps moving

forward with persistence and height of hard work. He is helpful, always open to discussions, and a very good team player aswell as a good leader. He has good positive attitude and never giveup. He is very cooperative, friendly and handles situations well which do not have much definition. Gopal nurtures a true passion for technology which clearly evident from the manner in which He applies himself at work. I am proud to recommend my friend cum well-wisher. I highly recommend Gopal and wish his good luck in future endeavors"

— **Suresh Kumar S**, *Student, Gandhigram Deemed University, Tamilnadu*, studied with Gopalakrishnan at Gandhigram Rural Institute

Contact Gopalakrishnan on LinkedIn